<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ruby on Harisankar P S | Ruby on Rails Developer</title>
    <link>https://hsps.in/tags/ruby/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Ruby on Harisankar P S | Ruby on Rails Developer</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>Harisankar P S</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 00:10:21 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://hsps.in/tags/ruby/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Sidekiq Graceful Shutdown in Fargate ECS</title>
      <link>https://hsps.in/post/sidekiq-graceful-shutdown-in-fargate-ecs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 00:10:21 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hsps.in/post/sidekiq-graceful-shutdown-in-fargate-ecs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Sidekiq is the gold standard when it comes to background processing. I have been using since I started working with rails. Sidekiq took care of lot of the complexity of the background processing that allowed developers to concentrate on just there code/business logic.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One of the beautiful features of sidekiq was how it handled exit (SIGTERM and SIGKILL).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://turnoff.us/image/en/dont-sigkill-2.png&#34; alt=&#34;Dont Sigkill&#34;&gt;&#xA;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://turnoff.us/geek/dont-sigkill-2/&#34;&gt;https://turnoff.us/geek/dont-sigkill-2/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When sidekiq received the sigterm commands it stops accept new jobs, and just focus on finishing the job it is doing now and incase it can&amp;rsquo;t finish, it will requeue the job to another available worker or keep it in the queue for another worker (or the same worker) to pick it up when available.&#xA;This was working so well for years on rails app I was working on, that I didn&amp;rsquo;t even care about it. The mina command would trigger a sidekiq restart allowing sidekiq to gracefully exit and then respawn with the new code.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The above app was running on two linux servers everything manually configured, but recently to keep up with the growth of the app we moved to amazon ECS. The app was containerized to a docker image, and made to run on about 12 Fargate Instances with ability to auto scale to 36 based on CPU and RAM usage. We grouped instances for various purposes 2 for heavy jobs, 2 for faster (more memory jobs), 2 for file processing, 4 for web, 2 for API.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>About Web Assembly. Example for Ruby Web Assembly</title>
      <link>https://hsps.in/post/ruby-wasm/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 May 2023 21:12:50 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hsps.in/post/ruby-wasm/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Any program to execute on a machine needs to be in machine code (1s and 0s). In some languages you compile the code directly to machine code, and some they converts it to intermediary code that runs on an virtual machine (which indirectly execute machine code). One of the biggest virtual machines in the world is a web browser. People write HTML,CSS and JS, and execute it by rendering the graphics and executing code on your machine. The browser have become so advanced that it takes care of security and safety so well. Thus being able to covert your program code or binary file into JS allows you to run your code on the browser and any machine that has a browser.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Now the idea of web assembly support in ruby (or any language) is not about writing website using ruby, though we can do that if we wanted to. The idea is to make a program or library that we have already existing in one language available for the web. If you can run ruby interpreter on your browser, then you can run any ruby code on your browser.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The things people doing with web assembly have been getting crazier. People are building more and more proof of concept ideas and apps in web assembly. The most exciting thing that impressed me recently was &lt;a href=&#34;https://webvm.io/&#34;&gt;webvm.io&lt;/a&gt;. A virtual machine is running on your browser with linux. You can run linux commands, execute a python program, etc. This is a full fledged virtual machine (the one you run using docker), running on your browser. There are more projects that does that now:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://bellard.org/jslinux/vm.html?url=alpine-x86.cfg&amp;amp;mem=192&#34;&gt;https://bellard.org/jslinux/vm.html?url=alpine-x86.cfg&amp;amp;mem=192&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://copy.sh/v86/&#34;&gt;https://copy.sh/v86/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;You can host a web server or a rails app inside an image, which will then run on your browser serving the content. (Note: networking is still not native, so most use web sockets to emulate a network and make internet available inside the container).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The potential for this is huge, you can technically turn any machine that can run a web browser (Chrome or firefox) into a server.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Validating YAML Files in Ruby</title>
      <link>https://hsps.in/post/validating-yaml-files-in-ruby/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Aug 2022 21:27:34 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hsps.in/post/validating-yaml-files-in-ruby/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;YAML stands for &amp;ldquo;YAML Ain&amp;rsquo;t Markup Language&amp;rdquo;. YAML is a data serialization language that is often used for writing configuration files.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In simple terms YAML is like XML or JSON, but for human beings rather than computers. I feel this is getting overlooked a lot, programmers need to understand that. Another human like configuration language I like is TOML (Tom&amp;rsquo;s Obvious Minimal Language).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In a static language (like crystal) you need to define the structure of a YAML or JSON file. Defining the structure also act as validation of its schema. Validating the schema is a good idea because it ensure&amp;rsquo;s that all the required data is present. Its better to know data is missing when your program starts rather than while it is running.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For dynamic language like ruby you can load a yaml file, and ruby will dynamically initialize it. It does make your life easier as a programmer. You don&amp;rsquo;t need to define the schema, and remember to update the schema when you add a new variable to your file.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;But defining the schema has its benefits -&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;For the User: It reminds then to have the configuration filled before running their program&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;For the Developer: It helps us to eliminate the configuration file as a possible reason for the program not running.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Access History in IRB</title>
      <link>https://hsps.in/post/access-history-in-irb/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Jul 2022 13:15:49 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hsps.in/post/access-history-in-irb/</guid>
      <description>Accessing the list of commands you have ran in your irb or rails console.&#xA;Running the following command in your console Readline::HISTORY.to_a returns the array of commands you have typed in console. After which you can treat it like any other array in ruby - search, sort, etc.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Using String in Active Record(Rails) Enum</title>
      <link>https://hsps.in/post/using-string-as-active-record-enum/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2022 20:10:36 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hsps.in/post/using-string-as-active-record-enum/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Rails model helps you define enum on a database integer field quite easily. The enum method which rails provide in its model is not an interface to the enum datatype available in some databases, but converting or using a integer field as an enum. Enum type or Enumerated type is user defined data type where you define the set of value the data type will have. If you consider regular or basic or primitive data types, they are pretty much like enum where the values it can hold is defined already by the language. Ruby dynamic type system does hide all this complexity for us while we develop.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Enum is quite useful when you want to make sure that only a specified list of values are saved for a field.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[TIL] Starting Ruby Method With Capital Letter</title>
      <link>https://hsps.in/post/til-what-happens-when-you-start-ruby-method-with-capital-letters/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2016 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hsps.in/post/til-what-happens-when-you-start-ruby-method-with-capital-letters/</guid>
      <description>Last day while I was browsing through some Java code online, I noticed that some method has names starting with capital letters. I Method names are written in small letters in ruby. This Java code made me wonder if there was anything preventing us from using method names starting with capital letter, in ruby. So I started my irb and wrote the following code.&#xA;1 2 3 def Test puts &amp;#39;testing 123&amp;#39; end And when I ran to call the method Test in the irb i got the following error.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Splat Operator in Ruby</title>
      <link>https://hsps.in/post/splat-operator-in-ruby/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2013 00:00:00 -0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hsps.in/post/splat-operator-in-ruby/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ruby splat operator (*variable) is used to convert an array of elements into an argument list.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Convert Short Urls to Long Urls</title>
      <link>https://hsps.in/post/convert-short-urls-to-long-urls/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2013 00:00:00 -0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hsps.in/post/convert-short-urls-to-long-urls/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;How to get a long/actual url from a short url?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Sometimes when we try to fetch short urls, using curl, we get a blank page as reply or a 301 ERROR. The reason being that there is no html file stored at that location,only a header with details ,on where the person who has opened the url would be redirected to.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;So to get the actual url or long url from the short url, we just have to read the location stored in the html header.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>When My Alarm Was Found to Be Not Working</title>
      <link>https://hsps.in/post/when-my-alarm-was-found-to-be-not-working/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hsps.in/post/when-my-alarm-was-found-to-be-not-working/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Due to some unfortunate events&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Loosing my phone&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;K-alarm crashing&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I faced a common problem for many people &amp;ldquo;No alarm to wake me up in the morning&amp;rdquo;. Like every single man, I love sleeping. So unless an alarm or person wakes me up, I will continue to enjoy sleeping - until the urge from my second passion (hunger) wakes me up.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Despite the fact that I love sleeping, my team mates at Ruby Kitchen, won&amp;rsquo;t be happy with me coming late to work. Challenged with such a problem, I did what every computer hacker would do.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wrote a program to wake me up, at 6:00 AM 😁&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Make Self Executing Ruby Scripts Linux</title>
      <link>https://hsps.in/post/make-self-executing-ruby-scripts-linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hsps.in/post/make-self-executing-ruby-scripts-linux/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;To run a ruby program we use the command &lt;code&gt;ruby&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;ruby program_name.rb&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ruby being an interpreter style language, each line is interpreted(read) one after the other and executable object code file is created for reuse like in case of compiler languages C, C++, etc.. To run a ruby code you need a ruby interpreter installed in your system.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
