<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>ruby on Harisankar P S | HsPS.in</title>
    <link>https://hsps.in/tags/ruby/</link>
    <description>Recent content in ruby on Harisankar P S | HsPS.in</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 19 May 2023 21:12:50 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://hsps.in/tags/ruby/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Ruby WASM</title>
      <link>https://hsps.in/post/ruby-wasm/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 May 2023 21:12:50 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hsps.in/post/ruby-wasm/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Validating YAML Files in Ruby</title>
      <link>https://hsps.in/post/validating-yaml-files-in-ruby/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Aug 2022 21:27:34 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hsps.in/post/validating-yaml-files-in-ruby/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;YAML stands for &amp;ldquo;YAML Ain&amp;rsquo;t Markup Language&amp;rdquo;. YAML is a data serialization language that is often used for writing configuration files.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In simple terms YAML is like XML or JSON, but for human beings rather than computers. I feel this is getting overlooked a lot, programmers need to understand that. Another human like configuration language I like is TOML (Tom&amp;rsquo;s Obvious Minimal Language).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a static language (like crystal) you need to define the structure of a YAML or JSON file. Defining the structure also act as validation of its schema. Validating the schema is a good idea because it ensure&amp;rsquo;s that all the required data is present. Its better to know data is missing when your program starts rather than while it is running.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For dynamic language like ruby you can load a yaml file, and ruby will dynamically initialize it. It does make your life easier as a programmer. You don&amp;rsquo;t need to define the schema, and remember to update the schema when you add a new variable to your file.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But defining the schema has its benefits -&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For the User: It reminds then to have the configuration filled before running their program&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For the Developer: It helps us to eliminate the configuration file as a possible reason for the program not running.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Access History in IRB</title>
      <link>https://hsps.in/post/access-history-in-irb/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Jul 2022 13:15:49 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hsps.in/post/access-history-in-irb/</guid>
      <description>Accessing the list of commands you have ran in your irb or rails console.
Running the following command in your console Readline::HISTORY.to_a returns the array of commands you have typed in console. After which you can treat it like any other array in ruby - search, sort, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using String in Active Record(Rails) Enum</title>
      <link>https://hsps.in/post/using-string-as-active-record-enum/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2022 20:10:36 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hsps.in/post/using-string-as-active-record-enum/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Rails model helps you define enum on a database integer field quite easily. The enum method which rails provide in its model is not an interface to the enum datatype available in some databases, but converting or using a integer field as an enum. Enum type or Enumerated type is user defined data type where you define the set of value the data type will have. If you consider regular or basic or primitive data types, they are pretty much like enum where the values it can hold is defined already by the language. Ruby dynamic type system does hide all this complexity for us while we develop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enum is quite useful when you want to make sure that only a specified list of values are saved for a field.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[TIL] Starting Ruby Method With Capital Letter</title>
      <link>https://hsps.in/post/til-what-happens-when-you-start-ruby-method-with-capital-letters/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2016 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hsps.in/post/til-what-happens-when-you-start-ruby-method-with-capital-letters/</guid>
      <description>Last day while I was browsing through some Java code online, I noticed that some method has names starting with capital letters. I Method names are written in small letters in ruby. This Java code made me wonder if there was anything preventing us from using method names starting with capital letter, in ruby. So I started my irb and wrote the following code.
1 2 3  def Test puts &amp;#39;testing 123&amp;#39; end   And when I ran to call the method Test in the irb i got the following error.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Splat Operator in Ruby</title>
      <link>https://hsps.in/post/splat-operator-in-ruby/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2013 00:00:00 -0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hsps.in/post/splat-operator-in-ruby/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ruby splat operator (*variable) is used to convert an array of elements into an argument list.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Convert Short Urls to Long Urls</title>
      <link>https://hsps.in/post/convert-short-urls-to-long-urls/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2013 00:00:00 -0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hsps.in/post/convert-short-urls-to-long-urls/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;How to get a long/actual url from a short url?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometimes when we try to fetch short urls, using curl, we get a blank page as reply or a 301 ERROR. The reason being that there is no html file stored at that location,only a header with details ,on where the person who has opened the url would be redirected to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So to get the actual url or long url from the short url, we just have to read the location stored in the html header.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>When My Alarm Was Found to Be Not Working</title>
      <link>https://hsps.in/post/when-my-alarm-was-found-to-be-not-working/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hsps.in/post/when-my-alarm-was-found-to-be-not-working/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Due to some unfortunate events&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Loosing my phone&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;K-alarm crashing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I faced a common problem for many people &amp;ldquo;No alarm to wake me up in the morning&amp;rdquo;. Like every single man, I love sleeping. So unless an alarm or person wakes me up, I will continue to enjoy sleeping - until the urge from my second passion (hunger) wakes me up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite the fact that I love sleeping, my team mates at Ruby Kitchen, won&amp;rsquo;t be happy with me coming late to work. Challenged with such a problem, I did what every computer hacker would do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wrote a program to wake me up, at 6:00 AM 😁&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Make Self Executing Ruby Scripts Linux</title>
      <link>https://hsps.in/post/make-self-executing-ruby-scripts-linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hsps.in/post/make-self-executing-ruby-scripts-linux/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;To run a ruby program we use the command &lt;code&gt;ruby&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;ruby program_name.rb&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ruby being an interpreter style language, each line is interpreted(read) one after the other and executable object code file is created for reuse like in case of compiler languages C, C++, etc.. To run a ruby code you need a ruby interpreter installed in your system.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
