<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Linux on Harisankar P S | HsPS.in</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/linux/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Linux on Harisankar P S | HsPS.in</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2022 22:58:41 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/linux/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Adding New Key per User to AWS EC2 Instance</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/adding-new-key-per-user-to-aws-ssh/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2022 22:58:41 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/adding-new-key-per-user-to-aws-ssh/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When we create a new server in aws, it allows us to generate a key pair and attach it to the server. Now imagine you want to share access to this multiple people in your team, but you don&amp;rsquo;t want to share your private key. This is what you need to do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Generate new key for each member of your team or ask each member for there public keys&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add it to the authorized_keys list in your servers &lt;code&gt;.ssh&lt;/code&gt; folder&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HTOP for GPU in Linux</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/htop-for-gpu-in-linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jun 2022 17:02:57 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/htop-for-gpu-in-linux/</guid>
      <description>htop/top is a useful command that helps users understand how much of there CPU (Different core)/RAM are being used. We would like to see the same for GPU there are tools that provide that, but sadly unlike cpu top/htop the ones for GPU are sadly fragmented. Based on your GPU vendor we have different tools to provide us this graphical info.
Note: I am talking about tools i tested in Ubuntu/Debian Linux</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Make Self Executing Ruby Scripts Linux</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/make-self-executing-ruby-scripts-linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/make-self-executing-ruby-scripts-linux/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;To run a ruby program we use the command &lt;code&gt;ruby&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;ruby program_name.rb&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ruby being an interpreter style language, each line is interpreted(read) one after the other and executable object code file is created for reuse like in case of compiler languages C, C++, etc.. To run a ruby code you need a ruby interpreter installed in your system.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Install Ruby via Source Ubuntu</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/install-ruby-via-source-ubuntu/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/install-ruby-via-source-ubuntu/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This blog post is for old style programmer who wish to install ruby via compiling the source code, like how I do it. This blog post is written in a just to know basis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The source code of ruby can be downloaded from ruby’s official website &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ruby-lang.org/en/downloads/&#34;&gt;http://www.ruby-lang.org/en/downloads/&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dependency for Ruby and Ruby on Rails : &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;libreadline, libyaml, libxml, libssl, zlib1g.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In ubuntu you can have these libraries installed via the command line ( or if you are so old fashion you may google and find the source code for these packages as well)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
