<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Hosting on Harisankar P S | Ruby on Rails Developer</title>
    <link>https://hsps.in/tags/hosting/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Hosting on Harisankar P S | Ruby on Rails Developer</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>Harisankar P S</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 18 Jun 2025 23:09:32 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://hsps.in/tags/hosting/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How I Use Tailscale to Host a Public App From My Laptop</title>
      <link>https://hsps.in/post/how-i-host-public-apps-using-tailscale/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jun 2025 23:09:32 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hsps.in/post/how-i-host-public-apps-using-tailscale/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I live in India, and getting a static IP at home isn’t straightforward. You usually have to go through customer care, sometimes upgrade to a more expensive plan, and even then it’s not always guaranteed. I wanted a simple setup to make one of my apps publicly accessible without paying a lot or dealing with all that.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;So here’s what I did. I used &lt;strong&gt;Tailscale&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;AWS Lightsail&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Docker&lt;/strong&gt;, and &lt;strong&gt;Nginx Proxy Manager&lt;/strong&gt; to expose my laptop to the internet, safely and securely. And right now, I&amp;rsquo;m running &lt;a href=&#34;https://easyclientlog.com&#34;&gt;https://easyclientlog.com&lt;/a&gt; - next.js application and &lt;a href=&#34;https://api.easyclientlog.com&#34;&gt;https://api.easyclientlog.com&lt;/a&gt; - ruby on rails application, using this exact setup.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;getting-a-static-ip&#34;&gt;Getting a Static IP&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I signed up on AWS and went to Lightsail. Picked Mumbai as the region and selected the cheapest Ubuntu server. AWS gives you a static IP for free (in lightsail) as long as it’s attached to a running instance, and the server itself is free for the first three months.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This server acts like a relay. It’s the public-facing machine. I don’t run the actual app on it, it just receives the request and forwards it to my laptop at home.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
