<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Harisankar P S | HsPS.in</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Harisankar P S | HsPS.in</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 13 Feb 2021 15:04:42 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Books I Read 2020</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/books-i-read-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Feb 2021 15:04:42 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/books-i-read-2020/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have seen many people write about the favorite books that they read in (2020, 2019, etc). I have a friend who has been posting regularly for almost a decade. Feeling inspired from this, here is my list of books that I read in 2020. I do like reading books, but I haven&amp;rsquo;t been able to keep up with as much as I would have loved to read. 2020 allowed me to catch up a bit, and hope to continue that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PS: Unlike most others who write their favorites, mine is pretty much just a list of books I read.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What You Learn From Binge Watching</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/what-you-learn-from-binge-watching/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Sep 2020 18:42:35 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/what-you-learn-from-binge-watching/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Binge Watching or Marathon watching is the practice of watching multiple episodes of a television program in rapid succession, typically by means of DVDs or digital streaming (Source: Oxford Dictionary). It has become a more common pass time or activity for the common people. It has become something that is planned and prepared to do alone or as a group. The availability of shows on demand through streaming service is the reason behinds huge growth of this activity, from a casual reference here and there to a more common social activity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is the joy of waiting for each episode, per week. Discussing theories for the next episode and reviews of the previous one with friends or other fans. This is still there even when you binge watch. Just that instead of the next episode you are discussing about the next season.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But what I wanted to write is not about what binge watching is or how it is (or it is not) good. What I wanted to talk about is, what I learned or noticed binge watching old TV shows or a long 10/11 season TV shows. The good points that I feel like is good to know or keep in mind in ones life. The one here is me of course 😁.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[TIL] Starting Ruby Method With Capital Letter</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/til-what-happens-when-you-start-ruby-method-with-capital-letters/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2016 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/til-what-happens-when-you-start-ruby-method-with-capital-letters/</guid>
      <description>Last day while I was browsing through some Java code online, I noticed that some method has names starting with capital letters. I Method names are written in small letters in ruby. This Java code made me wonder if there was anything preventing us from using method names starting with capital letter, in ruby. So I started my irb and wrote the following code.
1 2 3  def Test puts &amp;#39;testing 123&amp;#39; end   And when I ran to call the method Test in the irb i got the following error.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>When My Alarm Was Found to Be Not Working</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/when-my-alarm-was-found-to-be-not-working/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/when-my-alarm-was-found-to-be-not-working/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Due to some unfortunate events&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Loosing my phone&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;K-alarm crashing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I faced a common problem for many people &amp;ldquo;No alarm to wake me up in the morning&amp;rdquo;. Like every single man, I love sleeping. So unless an alarm or person wakes me up, I will continue to enjoy sleeping - until the urge from my second passion (hunger) wakes me up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite the fact that I love sleeping, my team mates at Ruby Kitchen, won&amp;rsquo;t be happy with me coming late to work. Challenged with such a problem, I did what every computer hacker would do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wrote a program to wake me up, at 6:00 AM 😁&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Model Update_attribute Update_attributes</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/model-update_attribute-update_attributes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/model-update_attribute-update_attributes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Lot of people might have a confusing between the functionality of update_attribute and update_attributes. The purpose of these functions can be understood from their name itself. the first one update_attribute would update a single attribute of the model&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Make Self Executing Ruby Scripts Linux</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/make-self-executing-ruby-scripts-linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/make-self-executing-ruby-scripts-linux/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;To run a ruby program we use the command &lt;code&gt;ruby&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;ruby program_name.rb&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ruby being an interpreter style language, each line is interpreted(read) one after the other and executable object code file is created for reuse like in case of compiler languages C, C++, etc.. To run a ruby code you need a ruby interpreter installed in your system.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setup Postgresql and Its Libraries to Work With Rails</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/setup-postgresql-and-its-libraries-to-work-with-rails/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/setup-postgresql-and-its-libraries-to-work-with-rails/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Recently lot of people have been asking me why they are not able to install the pg (PostgreSQL) gem even after installing PostgreSQL server in their system?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well the answer is simple, the pg gem, requires the PostgreSQL development libraries to build native extensions to communicate with the PostgreSQL server. Native extensions refer to building ruby extensions or wrappers for existing C or C++ library.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One can install the development libraries of PostgreSQL by installing the libpg-dev package.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Install Ruby via Source Ubuntu</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/install-ruby-via-source-ubuntu/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/install-ruby-via-source-ubuntu/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This blog post is for old style programmer who wish to install ruby via compiling the source code, like how I do it. This blog post is written in a just to know basis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The source code of ruby can be downloaded from ruby’s official website &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ruby-lang.org/en/downloads/&#34;&gt;http://www.ruby-lang.org/en/downloads/&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dependency for Ruby and Ruby on Rails : &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;libreadline, libyaml, libxml, libssl, zlib1g.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In ubuntu you can have these libraries installed via the command line ( or if you are so old fashion you may google and find the source code for these packages as well)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>