<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Thoughts on Harisankar P S | HsPS.in</title>
    <link>https://hsps.in/categories/thoughts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Thoughts on Harisankar P S | HsPS.in</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 22 Aug 2022 17:43:43 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://hsps.in/categories/thoughts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Which Language Should I Build This Software In</title>
      <link>https://hsps.in/post/which-language-should-build-this-software-in/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Aug 2022 17:43:43 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hsps.in/post/which-language-should-build-this-software-in/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Which Language Should I Build This Software In?&lt;/strong&gt; or &lt;strong&gt;Which language should I have this software developed In?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a question that software devs gets asked a lot by there friends/colleague who are not part of the software industry. This is my answer to them:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you had an idea of a novel? or a poem? which language will you write it in. Italian, Tamil, Bengali? Would you try to learn a new language because there are a lot of similar novels (anime) in Chinese or Japanese.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The best language to write your novel is the language you know the most.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What You Learn From Binge Watching</title>
      <link>https://hsps.in/post/what-you-learn-from-binge-watching/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Sep 2020 18:42:35 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hsps.in/post/what-you-learn-from-binge-watching/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Binge Watching or Marathon watching is the practice of watching multiple episodes of a television program in rapid succession, typically by means of DVDs or digital streaming (Source: Oxford Dictionary). It has become a more common pass time or activity for the common people. It has become something that is planned and prepared to do alone or as a group. The availability of shows on demand through streaming service is the reason behinds huge growth of this activity, from a casual reference here and there to a more common social activity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is the joy of waiting for each episode, per week. Discussing theories for the next episode and reviews of the previous one with friends or other fans. This is still there even when you binge watch. Just that instead of the next episode you are discussing about the next season.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But what I wanted to write is not about what binge watching is or how it is (or it is not) good. What I wanted to talk about is, what I learned or noticed binge watching old TV shows or a long 10/11 season TV shows. The good points that I feel like is good to know or keep in mind in ones life. The one here is me of course 😁.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
