<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Homelab on Harisankar P S | Ruby on Rails Developer</title>
    <link>https://hsps.in/tags/homelab/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Homelab on Harisankar P S | Ruby on Rails Developer</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>Harisankar P S</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 05 Sep 2022 18:29:12 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://hsps.in/tags/homelab/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Setup NFS Server on Ubuntu</title>
      <link>https://hsps.in/post/setup-nfs-server-on-ubuntu/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Sep 2022 18:29:12 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hsps.in/post/setup-nfs-server-on-ubuntu/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;NFS - Network File System is a distributed file system protocol developed by Sun Systems. It facilitates a client computer to have access to file/folder over network like a local folder. This is a easy/simple way to provide persistant storage for your docker-swarm or kubernetes cluster. In both these cases, the container (or pod) run on one of the available nodes (servers), and when we have replicas it will be running on more than one node. So local storage on the server is out of the question.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;With NFS we can directly mount the folder in the container. We can control everything from the configuration file. And thanks to the NFS storage we can increase and reduce node without worries as well.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Wildcard Domain in Pi Hole</title>
      <link>https://hsps.in/post/wildcard-domain-in-pi-hole/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Sep 2022 11:36:43 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hsps.in/post/wildcard-domain-in-pi-hole/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;PiHole is a DNS server that will block ads and website on a DNS level. This is an integral part of my homelab as it blocks a lot of ads on my phones and system, and also easily allows us to manage domains for local application.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For homelab I have a docker-swarm which is managed using portainer. I have a nginx proxy manager to map the ports to a proper domain, even provide https using lets encrypt.But PiHole doesn&amp;rsquo;t have a wildcard domain setting, hence after i set or before i set a domain my nginx proxy I need to add it to PiHole.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
