<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Shell on Harisankar P S | HsPS.in</title>
    <link>https://hsps.in/tags/shell/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Shell on Harisankar P S | HsPS.in</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2024 03:13:24 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://hsps.in/tags/shell/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Handle SSH Idle Connections Freezing shell or Getting Disconnected</title>
      <link>https://hsps.in/post/handle-ssh-idle-connections-handing-or-getting-disconnected/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2024 03:13:24 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hsps.in/post/handle-ssh-idle-connections-handing-or-getting-disconnected/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As someone who has been working with servers for over a decade and a half, I feel embarrassed to admit that I only&#xA;recently stumbled upon this setting. Throughout my years of connecting to remote servers over the internet, I&amp;rsquo;ve&#xA;encountered instances where connections freeze or break after a period of inactivity. Sometimes it happens more&#xA;frequently, while other times it never occurs at all. When I was in the US connecting to Amazon servers, there were&#xA;occasions when the connection remained stable for days on end. This led me to believe that the issue might be related&#xA;to the internet or the complexity of the network routing required to reach the server.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Adding New Key per User to AWS EC2 Instance</title>
      <link>https://hsps.in/post/adding-new-key-per-user-to-aws-ssh/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2022 22:58:41 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hsps.in/post/adding-new-key-per-user-to-aws-ssh/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When we create a new server in aws, it allows us to generate a key pair and attach it to the server. Now imagine you want to share access to this multiple people in your team, but you don&amp;rsquo;t want to share your private key. This is what you need to do.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Generate new key for each member of your team or ask each member for there public keys&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Add it to the authorized_keys list in your servers &lt;code&gt;.ssh&lt;/code&gt; folder&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Make Self Executing Ruby Scripts Linux</title>
      <link>https://hsps.in/post/make-self-executing-ruby-scripts-linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hsps.in/post/make-self-executing-ruby-scripts-linux/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;To run a ruby program we use the command &lt;code&gt;ruby&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;ruby program_name.rb&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ruby being an interpreter style language, each line is interpreted(read) one after the other and executable object code file is created for reuse like in case of compiler languages C, C++, etc.. To run a ruby code you need a ruby interpreter installed in your system.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
