<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>yaml on Harisankar P S | HsPS.in</title>
    <link>https://hsps.in/tags/yaml/</link>
    <description>Recent content in yaml on Harisankar P S | HsPS.in</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 22 Aug 2022 21:27:34 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://hsps.in/tags/yaml/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Validating YAML Files in Ruby</title>
      <link>https://hsps.in/post/validating-yaml-files-in-ruby/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Aug 2022 21:27:34 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hsps.in/post/validating-yaml-files-in-ruby/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;YAML stands for &amp;ldquo;YAML Ain&amp;rsquo;t Markup Language&amp;rdquo;. YAML is a data serialization language that is often used for writing configuration files.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In simple terms YAML is like XML or JSON, but for human beings rather than computers. I feel this is getting overlooked a lot, programmers need to understand that. Another human like configuration language I like is TOML (Tom&amp;rsquo;s Obvious Minimal Language).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a static language (like crystal) you need to define the structure of a YAML or JSON file. Defining the structure also act as validation of its schema. Validating the schema is a good idea because it ensure&amp;rsquo;s that all the required data is present. Its better to know data is misisng when your program starts rather than while it is running.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For dynamic language like ruby you can load a yaml file, and ruby will dynamically initialize it. It does make your life easier as a programmer. You don&amp;rsquo;t need to define the schema, and remember to update the schema when you add a new variable to your file.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But defining the schema has its benefits -&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For the User: It reminds then to have the configuration filled before running their program&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For the Developer: It helps us to eliminate the configuration file as a possible reason for the program not running.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
